VHISYHNU VIMILAN

Hi there! I'm Vhisyhnu and I have more 5 years of web and software development experience. I love working with people to do things bigger than I could accomplish alone. A quick learner in a working environment while able to meet targets and deadlines with good precision.

RELEVANT SKILLS

FRAMEWORK

- Angular16
- NestJS
- ASP.Net (.Net

Framework & .Net Core) • Javascript &

Laravel

DATABASE

- MSSQL
- PostgreSQL
- MYSQL
- Firebase

DEVELOPMENT

• Agile Scrum

LANGUAGES

- C#
- VB.Net
- HTML & CSS
- Javascript & Typescript
- jQuery

TOOLS &LIBRARY

- Postman API
- GIT & Bitbucket
- JIRA
- AzureDevops
- Docker

CONTACT

- +6011-27605409
- vhisyhnu97@gmail.com
- in LinkedIn: Vhisyhnu Vimilan

EDUCATION

Universiti Tenaga Nasional (UNITEN)

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE (SOFTWARE ENGINEER) (HONS.)

MAY 2017 TO FEBRUARY 2019

SOFT SKILLS

- Extremely Organized
- Fast Leaner
- Team Work
- Leadership
- Self-motivated
- Able to communicate in 3 Languages (English, Malay, Tamil,

Beginner Level Mandarin)

- Logical Thinker
- Time Management
- Adaptability
- Providing and accepting feedback

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

ILLUMINA PTE. LTD. (SINGAPORE)

MAY 2023 TO PRESENT

- Full stack web development using Angular, NestJS, PostgreSQL, .Net Core, MSSQL
- Worked with cross-functional teams to design and implement new features, resulting in a 30% increase in user engagement.
- Developed a dashboard to enhance inventory control and management which offer valuable insights into inventory resources.
- Reduced page load times by optimizing backend APIs and services.
- Wrote extensive unit tests and integrated Docker with development pipeline, resulting in reduction in bug-related delays and a increase in overall code quality.
- Vast knowledge and experience in Agile software development principles and practices
- Worked on projects that involved integrating third-party libraries and RESTful APIs.
- Architecture and Planning

Software Engineer

VIEWPOINT RESEARCH CORPORATION SDN. BHD.

JANUARY 2020 TO MAY 2023

- Web and Desktop application development (Full Stack)
- Worked in an Agile team of .Net developers for a fast-paced software development firm.
- Responsible for application software programming (C#, VB.Net, Angular14, AngularJS, MSSQL)
- Actively participate in Agile Software Development
- Enhanced the application's features to effectively fix the bugs and optimize the overall performance, reliability and efficiency
- Conduct research for new technology/ methodology.
- Work as a part of team to discuss, plan and implement new features and enhancements.

Junior Web Developer

IT WONDERS WEB DESIGN

FEBRUARY 2019 TO DECEMBER 2019

- Full stack web programmer (Laravel, Python, MySql)
- Planning and implementing tasks given by stakeholder of project following the due date given.
- Communicated with clients to implement Web Services
- Worked closely with product team on scope of future projects and innovations.